<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Henry's Blog</title>
    
    
    <link>/blog</link>
    <atom:link href="/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
      <item>
        <title>Tic-tac-toe Self-Play</title>
        <description>
          
          Code Here 1. Goal The motivation of this project is AlphaGo and its mechanism of self-play. So I took on the task of implementing a very simple self-play mechanism that is able to train 2 agents in mastering tic-tac-toe with only the visible state/reward information. No information on the rules...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2019 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-12-06-tic-tac-toe-selfplay/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-12-06-tic-tac-toe-selfplay/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OpenAI Gym - Acrobot-v1</title>
        <description>
          
          Code Here 1. Goal The problem setting is to solve the Acrobot problem in OpenAI gym. The acrobot system includes two joints and two links, where the joint between the two links is actuated. Initially, the links are hanging downwards, and the goal is to swing the end of the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-12-03-acrobot/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-12-03-acrobot/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OpenAI Gym - Pendulum-v0</title>
        <description>
          
          Code Here 1. Goal The problem setting is to solve the Inverted Pendulum problem in OpenAI gym. Try to keep a frictionless pendulum standing up. 2. Environment The pendulum environment has a continuous state space as follows (copied from wiki): State Type: Box(3) Num State Observation Min Max 0 Angle1...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2019 16:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-11-05-pendulum/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-11-05-pendulum/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>OpenAI Gym - MountainCar-v0</title>
        <description>
          
          Code Here 1. Goal The problem setting is to solve the Continuous MountainCar problem in OpenAI gym. 2. Environment The mountain car follows a continuous state space as follows(copied from wiki): The acceleration of the car is controlled via the application of a force which takes values in the range...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 18:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-11-04-mountain-car/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-11-04-mountain-car/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BrawlStars AI Series (Part 2) - Reinforcement Learning</title>
        <description>
          
          First and foremost, I must say, perception is harder than planning. This part, I will be attempting to apply reinforcement learning (RL) towards creating an agent that can play Brawlstars. The goal of the project is similar to part 1 —be a decent player and excert human-like behaviors. My personal...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2019 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-04-25-Brawlstars-RL/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-04-25-Brawlstars-RL/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>BrawlStars AI Series (Part 1)</title>
        <description>
          
          Brawlstars: https://supercell.com/en/games/brawlstars/ 1. Motivation I’ve personally being playing Brawlstars for over 3 months, and it’s a simple game to start considering the limited key combinations that it has. However, it’s fairly hard to master, considering the different mechanics each character has and the different maps in which each character’s play...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2019 01:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-04-20-Brawlstars-AI/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-04-20-Brawlstars-AI/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating a Policy Gradient (PG) Agent to Trade</title>
        <description>
          
          This is the first post that’s part of the series for teaching an agent to trade. I will evaluate different reinforcement learning (RL) approaches and share some findings along the way. The goal of the series is to learn RL by applying it on an actual problem that I can...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 01:55:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-04-04-pg-trading/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-04-04-pg-trading/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating Neural Networks with Python/Keras/Tensorflow to Predict the Future</title>
        <description>
          
          Previous Knowledge Required Understand what is a neural network (NN) and how it works conceptually. Python Basic understanding of what derivatives/gradients are Goals In this tutorial, I will go over 3 different approaches of creating a NN that can predict the prices of a particular cryptocurrency pair (ETHBTC). This include...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2019 11:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-03-20-ml-tut-price-prediction/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-03-20-ml-tut-price-prediction/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Asynchronous Advantage Actor Critic (A3C)-Reinforcement Learning -Laymens Explanation</title>
        <description>
          
          The A3C method in Reinforcement Learning (RL) combines both a critic’s value function (how good a state is) and an actor’s policy (a set of action probability for a given state). I promise this explanation doesn’t not contain greek letters or calculus. It only contains English alphabets and subtraction in...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-02-27-a3c-rl-layments-explanation/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-02-27-a3c-rl-layments-explanation/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>React Redux Intro</title>
        <description>
          
          I’ve been bugged by the native state management system in React that I finally had to take a stab at Redux. Here are some notes I took along the way to understand what Redux is and why we need it. First off, why do we need Redux when we already...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-01-26-react-redux-intro/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-01-26-react-redux-intro/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Career Paths in Data Science/Machine Learning</title>
        <description>
          
          This post is adapted from my answer on Reddit. I think there are various career paths that fall under “Data Science/Machine Learning”. This doesn’t mean there are 4 roles, it’s just how I see this industry; nevertheless, the more skills you possess, the better. Below are my personal thoughts based...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2019-01-10-career-paths-in-ml/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2019-01-10-career-paths-in-ml/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Looking back, planning forward</title>
        <description>
          
          It’s been a while since my last post. There’s just too much going on in my life that I didn’t get time to write down. Anyways, here goes nothing. The past 1.5 year has been really, really rough without any exaggeration. After switching majors, I’ve learnt a lot of new...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 08:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2015-12-03-looking-back-planning-forward/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2015-12-03-looking-back-planning-forward/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A few thoughts on choosing a career path</title>
        <description>
          
          When choosing a career path, the most important thing is to do the research and plan ahead. When we are talking about doing research for career cruising, we need to understand its industry. Its past, present, future. You don’t just wanna look at the present condition, because who knows what...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2013 09:52:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2013-12-24-a-few-thoughts-on-choosing-a-career-path/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2013-12-24-a-few-thoughts-on-choosing-a-career-path/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Different Life Experiences Bring Different Perspectives</title>
        <description>
          
          How I ever wonder, how does so many people have so many different answers to a simple “1+1” problem. To put the question into perspective, we have all heard of the “Standard Deviation” term from basic statistics, if not, this measures the variability of the sample or population data points....
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2013 08:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2013-11-16-different-life-experiences-bring-different-perspectives/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2013-11-16-different-life-experiences-bring-different-perspectives/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding the 'right' route</title>
        <description>
          
          It has been approximately 24 days since classes have started and I have gotten used to the work and life style in business school, the case method and socializing all the way. Most of the courses here are taught in the form of case studies, where the learning, supposedly comes...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2013 04:11:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2013-09-25-finding-the-right-route/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2013-09-25-finding-the-right-route/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Step Back and Rethink</title>
        <description>
          
          The thing that has been puzzling me for the few days was my career problem. I had come across some computer programming while working on my start-up venture. I really enjoyed working on technical problems, which made me rethink why I am here now, studying business.  I eventually decided to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2013 00:33:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2013-08-07-step-back-and-rethink/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2013-08-07-step-back-and-rethink/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>One Sentence Summary of Books</title>
        <description>
          
          Outliers - The curiosity of seeing one of my classmates do exceptionally well both in school and in life led me to reading this book; this book ties lots of real-world examples closely together and observing the information that people normally neglect. The Tipping Point - A awesome marketing, sociology,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2013 18:36:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2013-07-18-one-sentence-summary-books/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2013-07-18-one-sentence-summary-books/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>1st day at McKinsey</title>
        <description>
          
          My first day at McKinsey was a blast for myself. Simply because there were so much to see and so much to learn at this firm. I got access to lots of resources in its intranet and I was amazed by how much content is available to the employees regardless...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2013 17:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2013-05-15-first-day-at-mckinsey/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2013-05-15-first-day-at-mckinsey/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Dinner Talk</title>
        <description>
          
          Just had a wonderful dinner with a friend of mine. This guy isn’t just a friend, he is a mentor to me in some ways. The following is what I learnt from him tonight. A degree from a university is useful only if you really know how to apply the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 20:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2013-03-30-dinner-talk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2013-03-30-dinner-talk/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Movie Review - 'Accepted'</title>
        <description>
          
          Just finished watching this movie during my dinner break. It was awesome, to say the least! I was kind of unsure about my career and education these past years, because I found it really important to choose a “right” path for myself in my early 20s. Going to university/college is...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 17:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>/blog/2013-03-16-movie-review-accepted/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/blog/2013-03-16-movie-review-accepted/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
